<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../doc.xsl"?>
<doc title="Commiting files">
    <section>
        <p>
            A commit operation can publish changes to any number of files and directories as a single atomic transaction. 
            In your working copy, you can change the content of files,  create, delete, rename and copy files and directories,
            and then commit the complete set of changes as a unit.
            <br/><br/>
            In the repository, each commit is treated as an atomic transaction: either all the commit's changes take 
            place, or none of them take place. Subversion tries to retain this atomicity in the face of program crashes, 
            system crashes, network problems, and other users' actions.
            <br/><br/>
            Each time the repository accepts a commit, a new state of the file system tree is created. This state is called a revision. 
            Each revision is assigned a unique natural number, one greater than the number of the previous revision. 
            The initial revision of a freshly created repository is numbered zero, and consists of nothing but an 
            empty root directory.
            <br/><br/>
            A nice way to visualize the repository is as a series of trees. Imagine an array of revision numbers, 
            starting at 0, stretching from left to right. Each revision number has a file system tree hanging below it, 
            and each tree is a snapshot of the way the repository looked after each commit. 
            <br/>
            <img src="../../img/repository.png"/>
            <br/><br/>
            <br/>
            <b>How to commit files:</b>
            <br/><br/>
             <img src="../../img/menu-items/commit.png" align="left"/>
             <list>
                <item>
                    <b>1.</b> Select and right click on the versioned file(s) 
					you want to commit in the Solution Explorer.
				</item>
                <item>
                    <b>2.</b> Select <b>Commit</b> from the menu.
                    <br/><br/>
			        <br/><br/>                    
				</item>
			</list>
			<br clear="all"/>
			<br/><br/>
			<b>The Commit dialog:</b>
			<br/><br/>
			 <img src="../../img/commit_dialog.png" align="left"/>   
			 <br/>                    
             <list>
                <item>
                    <b>1.</b> Shows a list of all the files being committed. 
                </item>
                <item>
                    <b>2.</b> Type in your log message. All Lines starting with ‘#’ will be ignored.
                </item>
                <item>
                    <b>3.</b> Shows/Hides the <link url="examine_changes.xml">differences</link> between the 
                    modified (green), removed (red) and unchanged (blue) text.
                </item>
			</list>
			<br clear="ALL"/>
			<br/><br/>
			<b>The login dialog:</b>
			<br/><br/>
			<img src="../../img/login.png" align="left"/>   
			<list>
			    <item><b>1.</b> Enter your username and password.</item>
			</list>
			<br clear="all"/>
			<br/><br/>
			Notice how the status symbol has changed in front of the 
            item(s) committed in Solution Explorer to <img src="../../img/ok_file.png"/>
            <br/>
             Ankhs <link url="../keywords/output_window.xml">output window</link> 
             will show all the files that have been committed. 
            <br/>
        </p>
        <b>NOTE:</b> A Commit can not be reverted. 
    </section>  
     <section>
        <p>
            <hr></hr>
            <link url="reverting_files.xml">back</link> - 
            <link url="basic_work_cycle.xml">home</link>
        </p>
    </section> 
</doc>

