<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="doc.xsl"?>

<doc title="AnkhSVN FAQ">
    <section header="AnkhSVN Frequently Asked Questions">
        <section header="What versions of VS.NET does Ankh run on?">
            <p>Ankh currently supports both VS.NET 2002 and VS.NET 2003.  It is the same install file (msi)  for both versions. </p>
        </section>
        <section header="I get a message about not being able to attach to Solution Explorer?">
            <p>This is a known bug. It happens if you have your solution explorer window set to auto-hide. The only
            workaround is to not have it set on auto-hide while a project loads. Once the project is fully loaded you can
            set it back on auto-hide again. This bug is fixed in HEAD and the fix will be incorporated in the next release.</p>
        </section>
        <section header="What else do I need to have installed to use Ankh?">
            <p>Ankh links into the same libraries that svn.exe does, so if the Subversion repository is already created it is possible to use Ankh
             without ever installing Subversion at all.  However, with Ankh you cannot yet do some things, including but not limited to creating a repository,
              merging, copying or moving. It is highly recommended that Subversion be installed as well at this point.
              You can install Subversion from  <link  url="http://subversion.tigris.org">http://subversion.tigris.org</link>.  
                   Other than that all you need is VS.NET. </p>
        </section>
        <section header="I have Ankh installed but the menu entries are disabled or I don't see any at all.">
            <p>It is possible that Ankh was somehow disabled in the VS.NET Add-in Manager.  
            To enable it, in VS.NET go to the Tools menu and select Add-in Manager.   There should be an entry for  the AnkhSVN add-in that you need to check. 
            You should check the Startup box as well so Ankh will load when VS.NET starts, but not the Command Line box.
             After doing so green checks and other icons will become visible in the Solution Explorer form next to the files in your project that are 
             in your Subversion working copy.  </p>
        </section>
               <section header="I uninstalled Ankh, but the menu entries are still there, how can I get rid of them?">
            <p>You can run devenv /setup from the command line which will set VS.NET back to the default state. However 
            if you have any VS.NET customizations you may lose them.  </p>
        </section>
          <section header="Can I use Ankh with CVS?">
            <p>No, Ankh only works with subversion, it will not work with CVS. To use CVS with VS.NET Jalindi Igloo is available at 
                   <link  url="http://www.jalindi.com/igloo">http://www.jalindi.com/igloo</link>. </p>
        </section>
                <section header="There is nothing about my problem here!">
            <p>Don't despair. Either send a mail to our developers mailing list(dev AT ankhsvn.tigris.org) describing the 
            problem (in as much detail as possible) or visit us in our IRC channel #ankhsvn on the irc.freenode.net server.</p>
        </section>
    </section>
</doc>
