<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../doc.xsl"?>
<doc title="About Subversion">
    <section>
        <p>
            <b>Subversion's History</b><br/><br/>
            In 1995, Karl Fogel and Jim Blandy founded Cyclic Software, a company for commercially supporting and improving the Concurrent 
            Versions System (CVS). 
            Cyclic made the first public release of a network-enabled CVS (contributed by Cygnus software.) 
            In 1999, Karl Fogel published a book about CVS and the open-source development model it enables.
            Karl and Jim had long talked about writing a replacement for CVS; Jim had even drafted a new, 
            theoretical repository design, and had come up with a good project name. 
            Finally, in February of 2000, Brian Behlendorf of CollabNet (http://www.collab.net) 
            offered Karl a full-time job to write a CVS replacement. 
            Karl gathered a team together and work began in May. 
            Because Subversion was developed openly under a free license, it quickly attracted a community of developers.
            <br/><br/>
            The original design team settled on some simple goals. It was decided that Subversion should be a 
            functional replacement for CVS; it should match CVS's features, 
            preserve the same development model, but still fix the most obvious flaws. 
            And Subversion should be similar enough to CVS such that any CVS user could start using it with little effort.
            <br/><br/>
            After fourteen months of coding, Subversion became self-hosting on August 31, 2001. 
            That is, Subversion developers stopped using CVS to manage Subversion's own source code and started using 
            Subversion instead.
            <br/><br/>
            While CollabNet is credited with initiating and funding a very large chunk of the work 
            (it pays the salaries of a few full-time Subversion developers), 
            the project is still a typical open-source project, governed by the usual meritocratic rules. 
            CollabNet owns the copyright on the code, but that copyright is an Apache/BSD-style license which is fully 
            compliant with the Debian Free Software Guidelines. 
            In other words, anyone is free to download, modify, and redistribute Subversion as he pleases; 
            no permission from CollabNet or anyone else is required.
        </p>
    </section>   
    <section>
        <p>   
           <b> What is Subversion ?</b><br/><br/>
           Subversion is a free/open-source version control system. 
           That is, Subversion manages files and directories over time. 
           The tree of files are placed into a central repository. The repository is much like an ordinary file server, 
           except that it remembers every change ever made to your files and directories. 
           This allows you to recover older versions of your data, or examine the history of how your data changed. 
           In this regard, many people think of a version control system as a sort of time machine.
           <br/><br/>
           Some version control systems are also software configuration management (SCM) systems. 
           These systems are specifically tailored to manage trees of source code, 
           and have many features that are specific to software development (such as natively understanding programming languages). 
           Subversion, however, is not one of these systems; it is a general system that can be used to manage any sort 
           of collection of files, including source code.
        </p>
    </section>   
    <section>
        <p>
            <k>(from "Subversion: The Definitive Guide" <link url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/html-chunk/index.html">
            http://svnbook.red-bean.com/html-chunk/index.html</link>)</k>
        </p>
    </section>
</doc>
