<?xml version="1.0" ?> <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl"
href="doc.xsl"?> <doc title="Pilot Project Report">

    <p><b>Title:</b> Subversion addin for Visual Studio .NET</p> <p>
    <b>Employer:</b>  CollabNet - http://www.collab.net</p> 
    <p><b>Supervisor at CollabNet:</b> Karl Fogel, Software Collaboration Specialist - kfogel@collab.net</p> 
    <p><b>Supervisor at HIO:</b> Eva Hadler Vihovde - EvaHadler.Vihovde@iu.hio.no </p>
    <p><b>Developers:  </b></p> 
    <list> 
        <item>Arild Fines - arild.fines@broadpark.no   </item> 
        <item> Per August Krämer - per@perkramer.com</item> 
        <item>Kristin Borud - s106855@iu.hio.no</item> 
    </list> 
    <p><b>Duration of project: </b>09.01.2003 - 19.06.2003</p>

     <section header="Abstract"> 
		<p>The development of Subversion (SVN)
		addin for Visual Studio .NET will be conducted as a
		final year project at HiO in cooperation with CollabNet.
		First step is to make a .NET wrapper for the
		Subversion's client API, and thereby use this wrapper to
		create a Visual Studio .NET addin for SVN. We
		intend to write most of the system in the C#
		programming language.</p> 
     </section>

     <section header="Background"> 
        <section header="CollabNet">
            <p>CollabNet is a California-based company which provided the initial 
		    founding in 2000 to begin development work on Subversion and currently has several paid 
		    developers working on the Subversion project. CollabNet 
		    offers a wide range of products and services to improve software quality and 
		    accelerate time-to-market during product development. Their main product is 
		    SourceCast, which is a Web-based software development platform. 
		    Subversion is aimed to be the successor of an existing revision control system called 
		    CVS and CollabNet intends to make it a part of the SourceCast platform.</p>
        </section>
        <section header="Subversion">
            <p>Subversion is a free open source tool which makes it easier
            for several people to work within the same set of files. The
            files are placed into a central repository. The repository
            is much like an ordinary file server, except that it
            remembers every change ever made to your files. Each
            individual programmer checks out a working copy. During the
            development work cycle these working copies are updated and
            synchronised with the repository .
            </p>
        </section>
          
        <section header="Our project">
            <p>We wanted to do a project in the Microsoft's
		    .NET environment. Also, one of the group member had used
		    Subversion for several school and private projects for the last year.</p>
    		
		    <p>Currently you have to use Subversion from the command prompt. This is a very common
		    approach for UNIX developers, but developers on Windows are more accustomed to graphical 
		    clients. The dominant developer tool on Windows is currently Microsoft Visual Studio.NET, 
		    and integration into this environment would make Subversion a viable alternative to
		    a large number of Windows developers. We decided this would be a worthwhile thing to for our
		    final year project.</p>
    		
		    <p> After having defined the project we contacted CollabNet through the Subversion developer
		    mailing list, and they immediately showed interest in being the 
		    employer for our project and provided our contact person, Karl Fogel.</p>   
		</section>     	
    </section>

    <section header="Aim"> 
		<p>The aim of this project is to provide an
		integration for Subversion into the existing
		coding environment Visual Studio .NET. By making a addin for
		Visual Studio .NET the revision control system can be
		made available for a huge amount of new users. We
		also hope to make the .NET wrapper layer available as a
		standalone component so that it easily can be used in
		other applications in the future.</p> 
   </section>

    <section header="External conditions"> 
        <p>The group will have
        weekly meetings with the HIO/IU supervisor, Eva H.Vihovde
        Fridays at 14:00.</p>

        <p>Every Tuesday from 08:30 and Fridays from 13:30 the
        group will work at the dedicated school PC. The group intends to
        work together until all the group members are familiar with
        the software to be used. At a later stage in the project it
        will be possible to work separately at individual home
        computers as the communication easily can happen via
        instant messaging systems. The purpose with these meetings
        is to assess the quality of the work completed and plan
        the next steps.</p>

        <p>Throughout the project period we will continuously give
        information of project news and progress in an online
        diary.</p>

        <p>We have tried to define individual roles for each group
        member based on individual preferences and skills. Arild will
        be the main contact person towards the Employer CollabNet. Per
        will be the main contact person towards the computer
        department. Kristin will be responsible for a weekly resume to
        the HIO/IU supervisor Eva H. Vihovde in the group meetings
        based on contribution from all the group members. The roles are
        not definite and can be adjusted through the project
        process.</p>

        <p>To enforce an overall consistent look of the code we will
        compose a set of common programming guidelines.</p>

        <p>Subversion will be used for revision control both for
        the source code and documentation. Guidelines will be
        composed for how log messages are to be written.</p>

        <p>To ensure the sanity and quality of the system at any given moment,
        and to catch regression bugs we intend to conduct continuous
        unit tests using the <link
        url="http://nunit.sourceforge.net/">NUnit</link> testing
        framework.</p>

        <p>We hope to make the .NET wrapper layer available as a
        standalone unit for use in other applications. We also hope
        to provide <link url="http://nant.sourceforge.net/">NAnt
        </link> build scripts that will enable it to be built
        without requiring the user to have Visual Studio.NET
        installed. </p>

        <p>We intend to perform code reviews on a regular basis.</p>

        <p>Guidelines for how documentation is to be written in
        XML will be composed. The intention is to transform these
        XML documents into both HTML and into a format suitable for
        printing using XSL.</p>

        <p>There are some open source code for addins of common
        revision control systems and available code of addins in
        .NET in general which we hope to learn from.</p> 
    </section>

    <section header="Implementation choices"> 
        <p>We primarily intend to
        write most of the system in the C# programming language.
        However, it might be beneficial to consider alternative
        approaches in certain areas of the project. For example, it
        is conceivable that writing the .NET wrapper layer
        in Managed C++(C++ extensions for the .NET environment) will be 
        a better choice since Managed C++ offers better integration with C-based APIs 
        such as that of
        Subversion. Another alternative might be to use a tool called
        <link url="http://www.swig.org">SWIG</link>(Simplified Wrapper
        and Interface Generator) - a tool that generates wrappers for C
        and C++-based APIs automagically. We will have to research
        these alternatives more thoroughly and also seek advice from
        other people with knowledge in the area.</p> 
    </section>

    <section header="Conclusion"> 
        <p>Subversion integration with
        Visual Studio .NET can potentially make the revision control system
        available to a huge amount of new users. Also, creating a .NET SVN library
        will enable other developers to create Subversion clients in a .NET language.</p> 
    </section> 
    
    <signature>Oslo University College, 31.01.2003</signature>    
 </doc>
