<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="doc.xsl"?>
<doc title="Pilot Project Report">

    <p>"Title: Subversion plugin for Visual Studio .NET</p>
    <p>Employer:  CollabNet - http://www.collab.net</p>
    <p>Developers:  </p>
    <list>
        <item>Arild Fines -       </item>
        <item> Per August Kramer - per@perkramer.com</item>
        <item>Kristin Borud - s106855@iu.hio.no</item>
    </list>
    <p>Duration of project: 09.01.2003 - 19.06.2003</p>
     
     
     <section header="Background">
     </section>
        
     

    <section header="Aim">
        <p>The aim of this project is to provid an integration platform for Subversion into 
        the existing environment Visual Studio .NET. By making a plugin in Visual Studio .NET 
        the revision control system could be available
        for a huge amount of new programmers. The intention is to make the .NET wrapper
        layer platform independent so that it easily could be used in other applications.</p>
    </section>

    <section header="External conditions"> 
            <p>The group will have weekly meetings with the HIO/IU supervisor, Eva H.Vihovde 
            Fridays at 2am.</p>
            <p>Every Monday from 8:30 and Fridays from 13:30 am the group will work at the dedicated
            school PC. The group will work together until all the group members are
            familiar with the software to be used. At a later stage in the project it
            would be possible to work separately at individual home computers as the
            communication easily could happen via instant messaging systems.</p>
            <p>To enforce an overall consistent look of the code common guidelines for 
            source code is composed.</p> 
            <p>Subversion will be used for revision control. </p>
            <p>To verify the sanity of the system at any given moment, and to catch
            regression bugs (things that used to work, but breaks due to later changes)
            we will conduct continuous unit tests using the NUnit testing
            framework.</p>
            <p>We hope to make the .NET wrapper layer available as a standalone unit for
            use in other applications. We will provide NAnt build scripts that will
            enable it to be built without requiring the user to have Visual Studio.NET
            installed.
            </p>
            <p>Code reviews will be performed. (Guidelines for code review to be discussed)</p>
            <p>Guidelines for how the documentation to be written in xml will be composed. The intention 
            is to transform theses XML documents into both HTML and into a format suitable for 
            printing(XSL Formatting Objects) using XSL.</p>
            <p>The coding required to make the plugin is classified as advanced
            programming. There are some open source code for addins of
            common revision control systems and available code of addins in .NET
            in general.</p> 
    </section>
</doc>
