<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="doc.xsl"?> 
<doc title="Statusrapport for prosjektoppgave">

    <section header="Statusrapport">
    <section header="Gruppemedlemmer">
    <list>
        <item><link url="mailto:arild.fines@iu.hio.no">Arild Fines</link> - s104065</item>
        <item><link url="mailto:s113670@iu.hio.no">Per August Kramer</link> - s113670</item>
        <item><link url="mailto:s106855@iu.hio.no">Kristin Borud</link> - s106855</item>
    </list>
    </section>

    <section header ="Prosjektvalg">
        <p>Vi ville gjøre en prosjektoppgave som hadde noe med Microsoft's .NET å gjøre.
        Vi hadde også ved flere prosjekter, både her på skolen og utenfor, benyttet
        revisjonskontrollsystemet <link url="http://subversion.tigris.org">Subversion</link>.
        Subversion er et verktøy som gjør det enklere for flere personer å samarbeide om ett
        sett med filer(typisk programkode). Alle filer lagres sentralt på en server,
        og hver utvikler sjekker ut en arbeidskopi og jobber mot denne.
        Senere synkroniseres disse arbeidskopiene mot serveren.</p>

        <p>Vi bestemte oss for å finne et prosjekt som inkluderte begge disse
        teknologiene. Vi har i grove trekk tenkt å først lage en .NET wrapper mot
         Subversion's klient-API, og deretter bygge på denne wrapperen for å integrere
        Subversion i <link url="http://msdn.microsoft.com/vstudio">Visual Studio.NET</link>
        som en plugin. Som man kan se fra den responsen vi har fått, er det
        et stort behov og interesse for en slik integrasjon.</p>

        <p>Vi sendte følgende til Subversion's mailingliste:</p>
    </section>

    <code>
        Hi there

        I am a student at Oslo University College[1], and I am looking for a project
        for my final year. I need to have a project ready by the end of November,
        and the project itself starts right after new year and has to be finished by
        May.

        What I personally would like to do for this project, is to create a set of
        .NET bindings for Subversion(maybe in the spirit of #cvslib[2]?) and to
        build on those bindings to create a Visual Studio.NET addin for svn. I
        believe this is something which could be very useful if you want svn to be
        used among Windows developers. There is also the possibility of creating a
        plugin for Sharpdevelop[3] based on these bindings.

        The issue, though, is that this project needs to be performed for a "real"
        company - I cannot just sit down and decide this is what I want to do and do
        it. There is a degree of formalism to it requiring that an agreement exists
        between a company and the students that carry out the project.

        This is the main reason I am posting here. I was hoping that
        someone(CollabNet?) would be willing to fill this role. There isn't really
        that much responsibility on the employer other than providing a contact
        person. There is of course no charge involved, and the result of the project
        is the sole property of the employer to do with as he wishes(although I
        would personally prefer that it be released under some OS license).

        I have been doing C#/.NET for well over a year now, since the release of
        Beta 2. Other interests include C++, Java and Python - all of which I
        believe myself fairly competent at.

        I have been using Subversion for my personal projects since this spring, and
        this summer I started a project for myself to modify TortoiseCVS to work
        with Subversion. This project, although it was in a usable state and
        implemented most of the basic functionality, was put on the backburner when
        school started and I found myself having less and less free time.

        If someone is interested, you can reply by mail to me directly or follow up
        to this list.

        [1] http://www.iu.hio.no/index.phtml?lang=E
        [2] http://www.icsharpcode.net/OpenSource/SharpCvsLib/default.asp
        [3] http://www.icsharpcode.net/OpenSource/SD/default.asp

        --
        Arild Fines
    </code>

    <p>Vi fikk god respons, både fra <link url="http://www.collab.net">CollabNet</link>
    (firmaet som står bak Subversion) og fra andre firmaer som sa seg villige til å
    stå som oppdragsgiver for et slikt prosjekt. Her er noen av svarene:</p>
    <b>Greg Stein, <link url="http://www.collab.net">CollabNet</link></b>

    <code>
        &gt; CollabNet is discussing it internally, we'll get back to you soon :-).

        Our inclination is "well, certainly!" but since the person with actual
        signing authority for CollabNet (Brian) is currently out of the office, it
        is hard to give a definitive answer :-)
    </code>
        <b>Jeremy Denanny, <link url="http://www.roche-diagnostics.com/">Roche Diagnostics</link></b>
    <code>
        Actually, this is an incredibly useful project,
        and is probably the single most important thing
        that will drive svn adoption in Microsoft-centric development shops.
        Currently, (much to the chagrin of experienced developers),
        many MS shops standardize on MS Source Safe because it is bundled
        with visual studio, and has fairly good IDE integration.
        It's not my favorite source control tool - however, most shops are
        hesitant to replace it.  I'd like to see the .NET IDE 'integration'
        argument taken care of, and what you are proposing would (IMHO) be a
        great stride towards this.

        I'm interested in the time frame of the proposed project, as well
        as the details of the responsibilities of the company involved.

        I'm the Software Engineer / Configuration Manager for Roche Diagnostics
        in Roswell, GA (we're a global company, so my role is mirrored at other sites).
        If you send me further information, I may be interested in getting involved.

        Jerry Dennany
        Software Engineer
        Roche Diagnostics

    </code>    
        <b>Landon Clark, <link url="http://www.sawyermedia.com/">Sawyer Media Systems</link></b>

    <code>
        Hi Arild,
        If for some reason Collab cannot sign on for this work, I am 99% sure
        that my company can and also pretty damn sure we will not have a problem
        releasing the code under BSD/Apache like license, maybe even GPL.

        Let me know.  Thanks,
        Landon Clark
        Director of Development
        Sawyer Media Systems.
    </code>
    <p>Vi vil avvente et definitivt svar fra CollabNet. Dersom de viser seg å
    ikke være interesserte, vil vi kontakte noen av de andre.</p>
</section>
</doc>