<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../doc.xsl"?>
<doc title="Status">
    <section>
            Print the status of working copy files and directories
            <br/><br/>
            <p>
                <b>Description</b>
                <br/>
                Print the status of working copy files and directories. With no args, 
                it prints only locally modified items (no repository access). 
                <br/><br/>
                <list>
                    <item>' ' - No modifications. </item>
                    <item>'A' - Item is scheduled for Addition.</item>
                    <item>'D' - Item is scheduled for Addition.</item>
                    <item>'M' - Item has been modified.</item>
                    <item>'C' - Item is in conflict with updates received from the repository.</item>
                    <item>'?' - Item is not under version control.</item>
                    <item>'!' - Item is missing (e.g. you moved or deleted it without using svn).</item>
                    <item>'~' - Item is versioned as a directory, but has been replaced by a file, 
                    or vice versa
                <br/><br/>
                    The second column tells the status of a file's or directory's properties.</item>
                    <item>' ' - No modifications.</item>
                    <item>'M' - Properties for this item have been modified.</item>
                    <item>'C' - Properties for this item are in conflict with property updates received from the repository.
                    The third column is populated only if the working copy directory is locked.</item>
                    <item>' ' - Item is not locked.</item>
                    <item>'L' - Item is locked.</item>
                    The fourth column is populated only if the item is scheduled for addition-with-history.
                    <item>' ' - No history scheduled with commit.</item>
                    <item>'+' - History scheduled with commit.
                    The fifth column is populated only if the item is switched relative to its parent .</item>
                    <item>' ' - Item is child of its parent directory.</item>
                    <item>'S' - Item is switched.
                    The out-of-date information appears in the eighth column (only if you pass the --show-updates switch).</item>
                    <item>' ' - The item in your working copy is up-to-date.</item>
                    <item>'*' - A newer revision of the item exists on the server.</item>
                </list>
                <br/><br/>
                <b>Changes</b>
                <br/>
                Nothing
                

            </p>
    
        </section>
        <section>
            <p>
                <i>(from "Subversion:The Definitive Guide" - <link url="http://svnbook.red-bean.com/html-chunk/">
                svnbook.red-bean.com/html-chunk/</link>)</i>
            </p>
    </section>
</doc>